准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
黄雪王子
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
大家好
Hello
我是汉斯
I am Hans
欢迎观赏可鱼童话故事
And welcome to Fishy Fairy Tales
在哪来着
Now where were we?
对了
Yes
来
Here
为大家献上经典童话故事
Und now for a classic fairy tale
名叫  黄雪王子与七只小水母
called "Snow Yellow und the Seven Jellies"
黄雪王子
与七只小水母
从前  有一个快乐的小王子
"Once upon a time, there was a happy little prince
名叫黄雪王子
and his name was Snow Yellow"
嗨
Hi
哎哟喂
Whoopsie-daisy
快给我回去  疯疯小笨蛋
Get back in there, you cuckoo
黄雪王子住在一座城堡里
"Prince Snow Yellow lived in a castle
母
共住的是凯伦皇后  他的邪恶继主板
with Queen Karen, his evil Step-Motherboard"
我是故事的反派
I'm the villain in this story
幽默不
Ain't that a hoot?
故事始于一个美好的日子
Our story begins on a beautiful day
与其他日子一般无二
just like any other
早安  我忠心的臣民们
Good morning, my loyal subjects
我爱你们
I love you all
送你一点无价皇家珠宝
Here are some priceless royal jewels for you
再送给你
And you
送给你  还有你
And you and you
你好啊  许愿井
Hellooo, Wishing Well
准备好一大早一起二重唱了吗
Ready for our morning duet?
我准备好了
I-I-I'm ready
我对井许愿
I'm a well-wisher
许愿你平安
Wishing you well
许愿井
Wishing Well?
什么事
Yes?
我许愿你
I wish you
平安
Well
我许愿你平安
I wish you well
许下心愿  祝福你平安
Wishes of wishing you well
我许愿你平安
I wish you well
许下心愿  祝福你
Wishes of wishing you
祝福你
Wishing you
黄雪王子
Snow Yellow
我早上没更新完就不准唱歌
No singing until I've had my morning update
还是算了
Forget it
抱歉  继母皇后
Sorry, Queen Stepmommy
她哪弄来这么多水晶鞋的
Where is she getting all of these glass shoes?
王子
Hey, Prince
去洗皇家厕所
Start scrubbing those royal commodes
不然今天不准吃饭
or you don't eat today
洗厕所
Toilet duty
话说你怎么突然样子变得这么方正了
Say, why do you look so square all of a sudden?
我长大了  就长出了棱角
My big boy edges just grew in
多谢你注意
Thanks for noticing
再见  亲爱的继母
Bye, Queen Stepmommy
魔镜魔镜挂墙上
Magic mirror on my wall
这个世上谁最方
who's the squarest of them all?
皇后大人  你很方正
You, my Queen, are square
准确无误
'tis true
但黄雪王子才是最方正的
But Snow Yellow is the squarest
啵啵哔嘟
Boop-boop-bee-doo
我就知道
I knew it
你本来就不知道
No, you didn't
我告诉你了你才知
You didn't know anything until I told--
什么
What?
我要想保住世上最方正的地位
If I wanna stay the squarest in the land
就要让黄雪王子没资格再方正
I need to de-squarify Prince Snow Yellow
但要怎么办
But how?
我感觉挺有用
That works for me
猎人
Huntsman?
皇后大人呼唤我
My Queen doth summon me
您呼唤我前来了
You called for my personage--
我的
my most--
至高无上方正殿下
perfectly square Royal Highness?
你要去把王子带进森林
You are to take the Prince into the forest
把他的尖角剪了
and snip off his square corners
可是皇后大人
But, my Queen
那种事我可不能做啊
I could never do something like that
我打猎只找松露  不会剪海绵啊
I'm a truffle hunter, not a sponge slicer
那好
Okay then
我就把你圆角切了
I'll cut off your corners
这个海绵尖角
Would you like those sponge corners
是要厚剪还是精剪
thick cut or deli sliced?
快去
Gooooo
遵命  皇后大人
Yes, my Queen
虽然任务很讨厌  让他屁股有危险
Even though the task was a pain in the rump
猎人还是低声下气去抓黄雪王子
the Huntsman pursued Snow Yellow
like a cowardly chump
慢点儿跑  王子大人
Moderate thy haste, my Prince
你飞奔得也太快了
You're frolicking too fast
我跟不上
I cannot keep up
好像有谁没吃第二顿早餐
Looks like someone skipped their second breakfast
我先找下包包
Let me look in my satchel here
做好了
Here we go
放在金托盘上的蟹皇堡
A royal Krabby Patty on a golden platter
都送给你了
And it's all for you
你真好心  我不好意思把你搞残
You're too kind to mutilate
我做不到
I can't do it
加奶酪行不行
How about with cheese?
不对不对
No, no, no, no, no, no, no
你不明白
You don't understand
皇后要我剪掉你的尖角
The Queen wants me to cut off your corners
这样她才能成为世上最方正的那位
so she can be the squarest in the land
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
在哪
Where?
什么时候
When?
快跑吧  我亲爱的王子
Run, my sweet Prince
躲进树林里  永远别回来
Hide in the woods and never come back
不过你蟹皇堡就不用带走了
Leave thy Krabby Patty, though
跑吧
Run
我不想变圆
I don't wanna be round
我想一直方正
I want to stay square
什么
What?
不好了
Oh, no
是暗黑深林
The deep dark woods
也没那么可怕嘛  只要
They're not that scary as long as you--
天啊  好可爱的小巢啊
My, what a cute little hive
也许可以巢进躲里
Maybe I can hive in the hide
还是躲进
Or hide in the--
巢进
hive in the--
躲一阵子
hide for a while
在吗
Hello?
有没有人在家
Is anybody home?
得看一眼里面  确保安全
I need some eyes on the inside to make sure it's safe
加油宝贝
Come on, baby
老爸我得再找个地方住呢
Papa needs a new place to live
好像有小小的人住在这里
It looks like tiny people live here
太可爱了  但是乱糟糟的
It's so cute but such a mess
亲爱的小宝贝
Mon cherie
你这样可不行
Oh, no, you don't
我还得用呢
I'm gonna need these
七张小椅子  上面都刻了名字
Seven little chairs, each with a name
但这里也太脏了
But this place is a dump
真的很可惜
It's really a shame
本来这里正适合当我藏身处的
It would make a perfect hideaway
也许要是我打扫干净
Say, maybe if I clean it
巢主就会同意我住了
they'll let me stay
好耶
Hooray
洗厕所
Toilet duty
有这么一件事  绝对充满刺激
Now there's just one thing, with a ring-a-ding-ding
要想快乐干活  那就得
To get in the swing while you work, you--
没错
That's right--
用颤音高唱
warble
好吧
Oh, well
如果陷入困境  全身无力
If it gets tough and your energy is sapped
有时候打个盹最好
sometimes it's best to take a nap
王子浅浅打了个盹
"While the Prince took a quick nappy-poo,
此时住在巢里的七只小水母
"the seven jellies who live in the hive
正快乐地劳作着
were happily at work"
开采海底小花花
We mine flowers of the sea
酿出香甜水母酱
So we can make sweet jelly
我还可以赚大钱
And I can make me money
这花粉味道真怪
This pollen sure smells funny
别劳作了  你们这群白痴
Stop working, ya morons
已经五点了
It's 5:00
中咧
Bingo
万岁
Hurray
七只小水母接着回到家中
"When the seven jellies got home"
完全没料到会发现
"They did not expect to find
厨房进了一只打呼的怪物
a snoring monster in their kitchen"
进攻
Attack
好
Yeah
真是幸
How do you
会
Do?
你们一定就是这座可爱小巢的巢主吧
You must be the owners of this lovely little hive
没错
That's right
我的名字是
My name is--
不必多说
No, don't tell me
我在可爱小椅子上看到了你们的名字
I saw your names on your adorable little chairs
我猜猜看
Let me guess
你一定就是果果
You must be Nutty
正中红心
You hit the bull's-eye there
你就是蟹蟹
And you're Krusty
中奖了
Jackpot
芙芙
Puffy
没错
That is correct
呆呆
Dummy
还回来
Gimme that
老老
Cooty
你可太对了
You're darn tootin'
还有蜗蜗
And Gary
请问你是谁
The question is, who are you?
你来我们家干什么
And what are you doing in our house?
你一定就是
And you must be
烦烦
Drippy
很高兴
Nice to
认识你们
Meet ya
我是黄雪王子
I'm Snow Yellow
黄雪王子
Snow Yellow?
那个王子吗
The Prince?
没错  而且我有危险了
Yes, and I'm in a dangerous pickle
腌椰菜
这一切都始于
It all started when--
腌椰菜
Pickle?
这一切都始于
It all started when
魔镜
mirror
王子向小水母们叙述着他的悲惨故事
"While the Prince
tells his harrowing story to the jellies
而猎人则在欺骗皇后
"the Huntsman was feeding lies to the Queen
说自己剪掉了王子的尖角
"about cutting off the Prince's corners
皇后相信了  心满又意足
And she ate it up with great relish"
魔镜魔镜挂墙上
Magic mirror on the wall
现在这个世上谁最
now who's the squarest one of--
别浪费口水了
Save your breath
王子一样还是方的
The Prince is still square
什么
What?
提醒你一下  猎人是在骗你
The Huntsman is lying, if you weren't aware
骗你
Lying?
我这辈子从未受过如此奇耻大
I have never been so offended in my--
你要相信谁
Who are you gonna believe
信我  还是信那怪镜子
me or some loopy looking glass?
我当然相信你了
I believe you, of course
我相信你可以当鳄鱼饵
I believe you're alligator bait
不要
No
如果想要剪了某人
If you want someone cut right
就必须亲手去剪
you have to cut 'em yourself
穿这身奇装异服  王子绝对认不出我
The Prince will never recognize me in this wacky getup
我要把这球有毒海霸糊
I'll dip this ball of poison chum
裹进糖衣里  让人欲罢不能
in a candy coating that no one can resist
于是凯伦皇后悄悄前去
"So Queen Karen snuck away
七只小水母的巢  接着
to the seven jellies' hive and"--
我可以自己翻页  谢谢
I can turn my own pages, thank you
非常谢谢你们让我在这过夜
Thanks so much for letting me crash here a while
我晚上会做水母堡当晚餐
I'll grill jelly patties for dinner
万岁
Hooray
再见
Goodbye
晚上再见
See ya tonight
我也会想你的  蜗蜗
I'll miss you too, Gary
躲猫猫
Peekaboo
你好啊  方正到不行的朋友
Hello, my sickeningly square friend
可以借用一下卫生间吗
May I use your restroom?
当然可以
Of course
水母肯定不会介意
I'm sure the jellies wouldn't mind
看得出来你做了一桌美味晚餐
I see you've made a delicious dinner
有没有兴趣来个特好吃的海霸球
Can I interest you in a mouthwatering chum ball
配着晚餐一起吃
to go with that?
谢谢  好心的丑老太婆
Thank you, kind crone
可我不喜欢海霸糊
But I don't like chum
可我这海霸球可是裹了糖衣的
But my chum balls are dipped in candy
海霸味的
Chummy
吃一小口应该没事吧
I guess a little nibble wouldn't hurt
说实在话  还挺好
That actually tastes pretty good
这下你要永远脱水沉睡下去了
Now you'll be in a dehydrated sleep forever
我就会是世上最方正的那一位了
And I'll be the squarest in the land
忘带镐子了
Forgot my pickax
有个邪恶巫婆
An evil witch?
等一下
Wait a minute
贵重发箍
Pricey hairband
可拆卸鼻子
removable snoot
派对帽
party hat?
你不是邪恶巫婆
You're not an evil witch
是邪恶皇后
You're an evil queen
别吵  你个白痴
Keep quiet, you fool
给我回来
Get back here
皇后来了
The Queen?
黄雪王子有危险了
Snow Yellow is in trouble
黄雪王子
Snow Yellow?
皇后害他脱水了
The Queen dried him out
而且她好像还把水母堡全吃光了
And I think she ate all our jelly patties
坏皇后往那边走了
Bad Queen went that-a-way
一起去逮住那个坏皇后
Let's hog-tie that royal pain in the caboose
一定要甩掉那群笨水母
I have to get away from those jelly brains
下一部童话见
See ya in the next fairy tale
魔镜魔镜挂墙上
Magic mirror on the wall--
好好好
All right
你最方正了
You're the squarest--
有水母啊
jumpin' jellies
该按ESC键马上逃了
Time to hit my escape key
故事时间结束了
Story time's over
我干嘛把通道做成台阶
Why did I put in stairs?
你无路可逃了
Gotcha
不对
No
无路可逃的是
I've got
你们
you
来把你们这群水母压成酱
Time to mush these jellies into marmalade
螺丝刀
Screwdrivers?
你
Wha--
你们要干什么
what are you doing?
别动我螺丝钉
Not my screws
魔镜魔镜下墙来
Magic mirror off the wall
这个世上谁最快
who's the fastest one of all?
我
Me
好啊
Great
要遭七年霉运了
Seven years bad luck
我最方正
I was the squarest
世界待我不公
What a world
好啊
Well then
这下你翻不了页了吧
Cannot turn the page now, can you?
皇后施下的沉睡魔咒仍未解除
"While still under the Queen's sleeping spell
七只小水母把王子放上了海绵收纳盒
"the seven jellies placed the Prince in a sponge dish
避免王子发霉
to keep him from getting moldy"
我准备好了
I'm ready
万岁
Hooray
黄雪王子
Snow Yellow?
你还活着
You're still alive
还不穿衣服
And naked
没错
I sure am
你们几只小水母救了我一
You little jellies saved my--
赶紧穿上吧  小子
Put these on, boy-o
谢了  蟹蟹
Thanks, Krusty
你们几只小水母救了我一命
You little jellies saved my sponge
你可太对了
You're darn tootin'
我们把那个坏皇后拆散架了
We took that rotten Queen apart--
一根螺丝一根螺丝地拆
bolt by bolt
她再也烦不到你了
She won't bother you no more
那样的话
In that case
你们就能来我的巢过夜了
you can all crash at my hive
万岁
Hooray
一二三四
A-one, two, three, four
万岁
Huzzah
没错
Yes, indeed
他们从此过上了幸福快乐的
"And they all lived happily ever"--
我的手指头
My finger